Finding Aid for John G. Young papers, 1969-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John G. Young papers 1969-1976
Young, John G.
1 linear foot
8716 Aa 2
Professor of engineering, and director of engineering placement at the University of Michigan. Files relating to student demonstrations and protests over the visits of corporate recruiters to the University; includes handouts, correspondence, clippings, policy statements, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Professor Young (donor no. 6483 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John G. Young was professor of engineering at the University of Michigan. For many years, he had responsibility for the student placement in the U-M College of Engineering
The collection relates primarily to student demonstrations and protests over the visits of corporate recruiters to the University of Michigan in the period of the late 1960s to the mid-1970s. The series in the collection are Demonstrations and disturbances; Forums; University student organizations; and Miscellaneous.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Students--Political activity.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1961-1970.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.; Demonstrations--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Demonstrations--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Slogans.; University of Michigan. College of Engineering.; University of Michigan--Students--Political activity.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1971-1980.; Young, John G.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Demonstrations and disturbances
  - Litton Systems, January 1969 (Box 1)
  - Dow Chemical, February 1969 (Box 1)
  - Naval Weapons demonstration, March 1969 (Box 1)
  - Vietnam Moratorium, October 1969 (Box 1)
  - Hughes Aircraft, October 1969 (Box 1)
  - DuPont Corporation, January 1970 (Box 1)
  - DuPont Corporation (Central Student Judiciary Trial) (Box 1)
  - General Electric, February 1970 (Box 1)
  - General Electric (Robert Parsons case) (Box 1)
  - Lockheed Corporation, February 1970 (Box 1)
  - Dow Chemical, February 1970 (Box 1)
  - RAM strike, March 1970 (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Richfield, March 1970 (Box 1)
  - Dow Chemical, October 1970 (Box 1)
  - Honeywell Corporation, February 1973 (Box 1)
  - Exxon Corporation, February 1974 (Box 1)
  - Oil company protests, February 1974 (Box 1)
  - Central Intelligence Agency/National Security Agency, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Forums
  - Consumers Power visit, November 1970 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- University student organizations
  - Office of Student Services
    - Policies (Box 1)
    - Questionnaire on South Africa (Box 1)
    - Opinions and reactions (Box 1)
    - Newspaper clippings and related materials (Box 1)
  - Senate Assembly (Box 1)
  - Student Relations Committee (Box 1)
  - Judiciary Committee (Box 1)
  - Radical College (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - "Policy Committee" on placement (Box 1)
  - Research issue (Box 1)
  - Protest materials, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs: mainly student demonstration against visit of Exxon Corp. recruiters, 1974 (Box 1)